

Deepanjana Basu Ray

RESUME SUMMARY

12.5 years of experience in Finance operations and process improvement in the business processes of Order to Cash mainly in Billing, Cash Application, Collection- Dispute Management and also have good knowledge of Contract / Commercial Management as worked on Cost & Revenue Assurance, Corporate Governance Reporting, US & CA Sale & Use Tax Exemption. Co-ordinated with Global process owners, business / operation leaders to excel in KPIs and drive outstanding growth & results.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

3rd Jun 2022 - Present | Johnson Controls India Pvt LTD

Assistant Manager

Tax Exemption Team

- Leading a Team & Transitioned the US & Canada TAX Exemption billing work from Milwaukee Business Centre to Pune
- Creating of SOPs for various process & adhering the DOA & Approvals
- Checking & analysing of the various Tax Disputes & query resolving
- Liaising with various teams like Sales, Project Co-Ord, CMD, ACM, Collections to look into the root cause of Tax Disputes
- Liaising with E&Y team to seek tax advises & connecting with various IT &
 Application support team to make correction of the taxes based on Customer level / Product level in the system
- Handling escalations & query
- Managing the Internal Audit process
- Making Daily/Weekly/Monthly & other various reports based on data from SharePoint extraction & Power BI
- Mentoring & training the teammates as & when required
- Reviewing the performance of the team, keeping attendance record, leave record
 & reporting to the management as & when required
- Making & presenting ppts for Townhalls & Meetings

Billing- Customer Portal Service Team

- Assisting in raising the access request to different customer invoice upload portals
- Working on Different SOPs for the portal upload
- Assigning invoices to the Customer Portal Invoice Upload team as per their expertise in different Customer Portals so that the Invoice gets upload to the portal
- Have expertise in uploading Invoices after resolving disputes & queries in different Customer portals like: Coupa, Ariba, Corrigo & other different customer portals
- Addressing different invoice & Purchase Order related issues from the requestor
- Managing daily productivity reports & other reporting trackers
- Working on the On Hold report & Dispute Tracker & looking for ways to reduce the volume
- Working on different reports as well as different teams, collaborating with them so that the cash receivable, cycle dispute gets resolved and cash is realised as early as possible
- Working with Customer for Portal setup when customer requests their invoices to be uploaded through portal

Mar 2021 - May 2022 | BT E-SERV (India) PVT LTD

Commercial Delivery Management Analyst

- Validate costs versus revenue every month, working with Contract Accountant & Business Manager
- Review headcount vs Time bookings and call out anomalies

CORE COMPETENCIES

Order to Cash | Contract & Commercial Management| Revenue & Cost Assurance| Corporate
Governance | Process Improvement |
Dispute Management| USA & Canada
Indirect Tax (Sales & Use Tax
Exemption) | Invoice Upload
Management in Third Party Supplier
Portals



+919830380088 +919038328995



Deepanjana.br@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/deepa njana-basu-ray-86468515/



Temporary:

Building No.- M-16 Flat -1950, 1st Floor Maharashtra Housing Co- Operative Society, Yerwada. Pune-411006. Maharashtra



Permanent:

68, Tarun Sengupta Sarani. P.O.-Italgacha P.S.: DUM DUM Kolkata-700079. West Bengal.

EDUCATION

PGDBA in Finance

Symbiosis Centre for Distance Learning Qualified in 2019 with GRADE – A with 63.94%

BCOM (Hons) in Accountancy West Bengal State University Oualified in 2012 with 58.13%

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Hero of the month Award Feb 2023 in JCI
- Best Team award in BT
- Employee of the month Award in BT
- Bronze Award in Genpact

- Work with BM and CA to assist as costs saving/avoidance
- Cost Transformation activity highlight initiatives and follow through
- Review all WAN circuits/ Products for costs and revenue
- Assist the team with the inventory management
- Participate in team calls and managing stakeholder
- Participate in monthly P&L, and Forecast
- Assist with Mid-Month Forecast
- Work on the Variance and deviations
- Contribute to monthly Contract Governance Report preparation
- Billing and tracking of Purchase Orders & Invoices which needs to be improved in terms of process and control
- Understand the contract and products we provide and help BM with contractual issues,
 Change Control Notes
- Prepare Report, Spreadsheets, Presentation as required for Data Analysis

11th Sept 2017- Mar 2021 | BT E-SERV (India) PVT LTD

Associate

- Clearing off the payments/postings which the end customer makes through different billing systems
- Downloading the bank statement and doing the Remittance Advise Indexing
- Working on the Postings/Queries/Credit transfers/Refund that comes in the work flow
- Resolving the issues/queries that come is Mailbox
- Responsible for managing and collections of all the accounts receivable from the customer
- Downloading the Aged Debt Report, Cash Application Report
- Pulling credit hold report and releasing them after checking the payment transaction
- Monitoring the accounts on daily basis which we find in the Aged Debt Report
- Maintaining the historical trend of the customer payment and keeping on updating it
- Liaising with different teams in order to resolve the dispute or discrepancy for cash receivable
- Handling queries of the customer for easy in flow of cash receivables
- Sending gentle reminders as well as chasers for the past due invoices
- Update the profile of the customer as per the status of their payment
- Also have been part of Women Diversity Committee, BCP Team, Fun SPOC & ERT member where my role lies in looking after the needs of the committee
- Complete 2 process improvement plans and implemented it successfully in the process.

20th Jun 2014 - 7th Sept 2017 | GENPACT INDIA PVT LTD

Process Associate then promoted to Process Developer

- Worked in Accounts Receivable domain for a UK based Process in Cash Management team (O2C) Interrogating and matching the account details and bill statement on daily basis for which the payment has been made by the end users.
- To process cash application of the end users' bill to their correct accounts and clear their bills for which payment is made
- Adjusting excess cash provided by end users by taking their authorization via calling them directly or emailing them.
- Communicating with the client as well as the end users about their bill statement and payments and ongoing process on daily basis.
- Managing bill payments as well as bond payments
- Doing Remittance advice indexing.
- Refunding excess amount left on account through Card/BACS/Cheques.
- Doing Internal Audit and Duplicate Check.

1st July 2011 - 19th June 2014 | Z2PLUS PLACEMENT & SECURITY AGENCY PVT LTD

Finance Assistant

- Recording all the business transaction using Tally
- Preparing and updating Bank Reconciliation Statement
- Looking after the petty cash requirement of the company
- Physical cash verification & Bill payables updating
- Reconciliation of inter office transaction & party accounts
- Account reconciliation with Debtor & Creditor
- Making monthly salary statement
- Assisting in Finalizing of Accounts

STRENGHT

- Stakeholder Management
- Ability to work under stress
- Endeavour for Continuous
 Improvement
- Very interactive that helped me to make new relations & business in the Company
- Have ability to identify and analyse the problems & techniques to resolve it
- Exercise leadership to boost the capability of the team

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- AIKF Black Belt holder in Karate (1st DAN) &Bronze medallist in National Level Competition in Muay Thai in 2009.
- Always been an active member of different committees in office be it Fun SPOC, Suraksha or Sports Committee

TECHNICAL SKILLS

MS OFFICE Apps | Dise CMP | RUMBA |
PANCREDIT | SALESFORCE | GLOSSI |
Concert | Coupa Supplier Portal | Ariba |
Corrigo | Third party Supplier Portals
|Ace ORACLE | Webform | Power BI |
Barclay's Banking Portal | Vertex Q & O
Series | LEAN & JDI certified and has given
multiple process improvement plans

LANGUAGES

English (Business Proficient)
Bengali (Mother Tongue)
Hindi (Business Proficient)
Telugu (Beginner)
Marathi (Beginner)